<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<page>
	<useTemplate>false</useTemplate>
	<template></template>
	<usehtml>true</usehtml>
	<title>Liam Anderson - Curriculum Vitae</title>
	<description>Liam Anderson, CV, Resume</description>
	<contentTitle></contentTitle>
	<content><![CDATA[<h1 class="tc grey">Curriculum Vitae</h1>
		<h2 class="grey">PROFILE SUMMARY</h2>
		<p class="grey">I am a full-stack web developer who is passionate about information security. I have been working in the marketing industry and freelance for four years specialising in front end development and automation using technologies such as python, PHP, SQL and NodeJS to build efficient frontends and websites that have worked to increase conversions through affective UI Design and Granular telemetry tracking. Working freelance and as the sole developer for an agency I am ideally looking for a workplace that allows me to work with similar professionals and likeminded people work and work on much more complex and advanced projects, enhancing my skills and progressing further learning. </p>
		<h2 class="grey">SKILLS AND ABILITIES</h2>
		<p class="grey">Willingness to learn, Commercial awareness, Familiar with process proposal and writing, Interpersonal skills including meeting clients and explaining technical details.</p>
		<p class="grey">Proficiency with Linux and Windows servers, knowledge of networking and some understanding of Cisco systems, Troubleshooting common issues in a windows environment, An understanding of digital marketing and strategies.</p>
		<p class="grey">I am confident in and specialize in the following languages and libraries: Bash, Batch scripting C#, VB.net JS, jQuery HTML, CSS PHP, Python, Django SQL</p>
		<h2 class="grey">EXPERIENCE</h2>
		<h3 class="grey">WEB DEVELOPER | CUMBRIA UNIVERSITY | AUGUST 2019 <span class="date" class="grey">CURRENT</span class="grey"></h3>
		<p class="grey">First taken on to help complete a web redesign, Accessibility project uncomplete by the previous team as well as with developing processes and methods for making changes and updating information for purposes of CMA(Competition and Markets Authority)</p>
		<h3 class="grey">JUNIOR DEVELOPER | NOVI.DIGITAL <span class="date" class="grey">DECEMBER 2015 - APRIL 2019</span class="grey"></h3>
		<p class="grey">Initially my position started as a web development apprentice where I completed a Level 3 and level 4 &ldquo;Advanced Apprenticeship in IT, Software, Web &amp; Telecoms Professionals&rdquo; where I focused on C#.</p>
		<p class="grey">Around six months into the apprenticeship a change in staffing meant that I became the only developer for the company, taking on more roles as the sole technical lead for the at the time SEO247 now novi.digital.</p>
		<p class="grey">In my position at novi, I worked on and speared projects to help the teams workload with automation and to automate manual tasks including a javascript library that can be universally applied to websites and track conversions and interactions granularly.</p>
		<h2 class="grey">EDUCATION</h2>
		<h3 class="grey">LEVEL 4 DIPLOMA IN IT, SOFTWARE, WEB &amp; TELECOMS PROFESSIONALS | JULY 2018 | BALTIC</h3>
		<h3 class="grey">LEVEL 3 DIPLOMA IN IT, SOFTWARE, WEB &amp; TELECOMS PROFESSIONALS | JAN 2017 | BALTIC</h3>
		<h3 class="grey">LEVEL 2 DIPLOMA ICT PRACTITIONER | JUNE 2014 | LANCASTER AND MORECAMBE COLLEGE</h3>
		<h2 class="grey">NOTABLE ACHIVEMENTS</h2>
		<ul class="grey">
			<li class="grey">Picked up a four-month backlog of changes for the university website in six weeks form working with my colleagues to implement better processes and managing expectations of academics</li>
			<li class="grey">Worked on several successful development projects with multinational organisations</li>
			<li class="grey">Completed my foundation degree education to distinction level</li>
			<li class="grey">In college, I gave a presentation to Wroclaw University on the importance of helping the older generation understand concepts and paradigms in technology to better use computers and upskill</li>
		</ul>
		<h2 class="grey">HOBBIES AND INTERESTS</h2>
		<p class="grey">I consider myself a &ldquo;Tinkerer/Maker&rdquo; with an interest in anything mechanical or electronic, I commonly find myself accidentally spending way more time than I initially intended learning something new or integral to an ongoing project</p>
		<p class="grey">When I&rsquo;m not learning or tinkering, I will be engaging I&rsquo;m some sort of outdoor activity like mountain biking, hiking or riding my motorbike.</p></contentTitle>
	]]></content>
</page>